Guide to the Letters to Stephen McKenna
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Letters to Stephen McKenna
1917-1939
GEN MSS 316
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.4
(1 box)
Letters to the English novelist Stephen McKenna, principally from other authors, including Alfred Austin, Arnold Bennett, John Drinkwater, John Galsworthy, Compton Mackenzie, John Masefield, Arthur Wing Pinero, Frank Swinnerton, Hugh Walpole and Arthur Waugh. Many of the letters concern invitations to literary dinners and other social events.
McKenna, Stephen, 1888-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from David J. Holmes on the Philip M. Neufeld Fund in 1997.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Letters to Stephen McKenna consists of social and literary letters addressed to the English novelist. The papers span the dates 1917-1939 and correspondents include Alfred Austin, Augustine Birrell, John Drinkwater, John Galsworthy, Compton Mackenzie, Arthur Wing Pinero, John Sargeaunt, and Frank Swinnerton. Many of the notes concern dinner invitations and other social engagements.
Authors, English -- 20th Century; Austin, Alfred, 1835-1913; Bennett, Arnold, 1867-1931; Drinkwater, John, 1882-1937; Galsworthy, John, 1867-1933; Mackenzie, Compton, 1883-1972; Masefield, John, 1878-1967; McKenna, Stephen, 1888-; Pinero, Arthur Wing, 1855-1934; Swinnerton, Frank, 1884-1982; Walpole, Hugh, 1884-1941; Waugh, Arthur, 1866-1943
- Letters to Stephen McKenna, 1922 may 29
  - Albanesi, E. Maria, 1922 may 29 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Austin, Alfred, n.y. Dec 6 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Bennett, Arnold, 1922 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Birrell, Augustine, 1917 Nov 10 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Buckmaster, Stanley Owen Buckmaster, Viscount, 1919 Feb 21 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Clifton, Elizabeth, n.d. (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Couperus, Louis, 1922 Oct 13 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - de Broke, Willoughby, 1922 Jun 3 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Delafield, Elizabeth M., 1927 May, Jun (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Drinkwater, John, 1921, 1923 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Galsworthy, John, 1929 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Graham, Stephen, 1926 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Harrison, Frederick, 1922 Jun 1 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Hawkins, Anthony H., 1919-29 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Hewart, Gordon Hewart, Baron, 1918, 1919 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Horne, [E. S.], 1920 Jun 22 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Hutchinson, A. S. M., 1926, 1935 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Leish, Montague?, 1918 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Locke, William, 1927 May 24 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Mackenzie, Compton, 1925, 1926 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Macpherson, Ian, 1917, 1919 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Marie Louise, Princess, 1920 Dec 6 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Masefield, John, 1938 Oct 21 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Maxwell, W. B., 1922, 1924 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Mersey, John Charles Bigham, Viscount, 1918 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Morison, ----, 1919 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Munro, Robert, 1919 May? 30 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - O'Connor, T. P., 1921 May 30 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Page, T. E., n.y. Feb 27 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Palmer, Herbert, 1936 Oct 7 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Pickford, W., 1918 Jan 14 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Pinero, Arthur Wing, 1921 Jun 11 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Runciman, Walter, 1919 Feb 21 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - "Russell, Elizabeth," Countess, 1919-22, n.d. (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Rutherston, Albert, n.d. (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Sankey, John, 1918 Jan 15 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Sargeaunt, John, 1917 Nov 10 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Shortt, Edward, 1917-22 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Southwark, Bishop of, 1918 Jan 17 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Swinnerton, Frank, 1939, n.d. (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Walpole, Hugh, 1922 May 31 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Walters, J. Tudor?, 1917-22 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Waugh, Arthur, 1932 Jan 9 (Box 1, Folder +)
  - Unidentified, 1918-25, n.d. (Box 1, Folder +)